African, Afro-Caribbean, and African American, Native American and Pacific Rim Arts Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
African, Afro-Caribbean, and African American, Native American and Pacific Rim Arts Slide Collection
1960-2005
VRC 1650
Yale University Arts Library
5
28 boxes in 5 containers
Collection consists of color and black and white 35 mm slides of the arts of African, Native American, and Pacific Rim cultures, including Australia and New Zealand, as well as Afro-Brazilian, Afro-cuban, Afro-Haitian, Afro-Mexican, Afro-Portuguese, Afro-Surinam, and Afro-American arts.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of color and black and white 35 mm slides of the arts of African, Native American, and Pacific Rim cultures, including Australia and New Zealand, as well as Afro-Brazilian, Afro-cuban, Afro-Haitian, Afro-Mexican, Afro-Portuguese, Afro-Surinam, and Afro-American arts.
Arrangement
Arranged into four principal sub-collections: Africa, Afro-, Native American and Pacific Rim. Sub-arranged principally by location.
Arts, African; Indian arts -- North America; Pacific Area -- Antiquities; Blacks in art; African American art; Slides; Reproductions
- Africa (Box 1)
  - General [Slide box 1] (Box 1)
    - Various (Box 1)
    - Comparisons (Box 1)
    - Early Depictions (Box 1)
    - Early Photographs (Box 1)
- Arts (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - West Africa (Box 1)
    - Various (Box 1)
    - Tribes and/or Peoples [Slide box 2] (Box 1)
      - Various (Box 1)
      - Abomey Tribe (Box 1)
      - Abua People (Box 1)
      - Agni People (Box 1)
      - Akan Group (Box 1)
      - Arun People (Box 1)
      - Ashanti People (Box 1)
      - Attie People (Box 1)
      - Babanki People (Box 1)
      - Bafo Tribe (Box 1)
      - Bafut People (Box 1)
      - Baga Tribe (Box 1)
      - Bamana People (Mali) (Box 1)
      - Bamileke Tribe (Box 1)
      - Bambara Tribe (Box 1)
      - Bamum Tribe [Slide box 3] (Box 1)
      - Bangwa Tribe (Box 1)
      - Bariba Tribe (Box 1)
      - Baule People (Box 1)
      - Benin Tribe (Box 1)
      - Bete Tribe (Box 1)
      - Bijago People (Box 1)
      - Bobo Tribe [Slide boxes 3-4] (Box 1)
      - Borodougon People [Slide box 4] (Box 1)
      - Bozo People (Box 1)
      - Cameroon (Box 1)
      - Cross River People (Box 1)
      - Dahomey People (Box 1)
      - Dan Tribe [Slide boxes 4-5] (Box 1)
      - Diola People [Slide box 5] (Box 1)
      - Dida People (Box 1)
      - Dogon People (Box 1)
      - Ejagham People (Box 1)
      - Ekoi People (Box 1)
      - Eshupum People (Box 1)
      - Ewe People (Box 1)
      - Fang Tribev (Box 1)
      - Fanti People [Slide box 6] (Box 1)
      - Fon People (Box 1)
      - Fulani Tribe (Box 1)
      - Ga People (Box 1)
      - Gabin People (Box 1)
      - Ganguela People (Box 1)
      - Gola People (Box 1)
      - Gourma People (Box 1)
      - Grebo People (Box 1)
      - Guro Tribe (Box 1)
      - Ham People (Box 1)
      - Hausa People (Box 1)
      - Ibibio People (Box 1)
      - Ibo People (Box 1)
        General
        Xx preferred spelling now Igbo, see under Igbo
      - Ife People (Box 1)
      - Igbo People [Slide boxes 6-7] (Box 1–2)
        Xx for Owerri district mbari houses see Architecture Africa West: Owerri district
      - Kabre People [Slide box 7] (Box 2)
      - Kaka People (Box 2)
      - Kalabari People (Box 2)
      - Kasena People (Box 2)
      - Kissi People (Box 2)
      - Kofyar People (Box 2)
      - Kusasi People (Box 2)
      - Kutep People (Box 2)
      - Landuma People (Box 2)
      - Lobi People (Box 2)
      - Lyela People (Box 2)
      - Mahongwe People (Box 2)
      - Malinke People (Box 2)
      - Mama People (Box 2)
      - Mandinka People (Box 2)
      - Manjaco People (Box 2)
      - Marka People (Box 2)
      - Maouris People (Box 2)
      - Mendi Tribe (Box 2)
      - Mossi Tribe (Box 2)
      - Nafana People (Box 2)
      - Ngounie River People (Box 2)
      - Nok Tribe (Box 2)
      - Nupe Tribe [Slide box 8] (Box 2)
      - Nsaw People (Box 2)
      - Ogowe River Area (Box 2)
      - Quimbele People (Box 2)
      - Sao People (Box 2)
      - Senufo Tribe (Box 2)
      - Sherbro People (Box 2)
      - Somba Tribe (Box 2)
      - Somolo People (Box 2)
      - Songhai People (Box 2)
      - Susu Tribe (Box 2)
      - Temne People (Box 2)
      - Tera People (Box 2)
      - Tikar People (Box 2)
      - Tiv Tribe (Box 2)
      - Tsogo People (Box 2)
      - Tuareg People (Box 2)
      - Vuvi People (Box 2)
      - We Tribe (Box 2)
      - Widekum People (Box 2)
      - Woga People (Box 2)
      - Woloff People (Box 2)
      - Yoruba Tribe [Slide boxes 8-9] (Box 2)
        - Anago [Slide box 9] (Box 2)
        - Aworri (Box 2)
        - Dasha (Box 2)
        - Efon (Box 2)
        - Egba (Box 2)
        - Egbado [Slide boxes 9-10] (Box 2)
        - Ekiti [Slide box 10] (Box 2)
        - Ijebu (Box 2)
        - Ketu (Box 2)
        - Owo (Box 2)
        - Oyo (Box 2)
  - Central Africa (Box 2)
    - Various [Slide boxes 10-11] (Box 2)
    - Tribes and/or People [Slide box 11] (Box 2)
      - Various (Box 2)
      - Bembe (Box 2)
      - Bena-Konji People (Box 2)
      - Bena Lulua Tribe (Box 2)
      - Biomba People (Box 2)
      - Holo Tribe (Box 2)
      - Huana People (Box 2)
      - Jokwe (Box 2)
        Xx Tu-Chockwe
      - Kongo People (Box 2)
      - Kota People (Box 2)
      - Kuba (Box 2)
      - Kuyu Tribe (Box 2)
      - Kwele People (Box 2)
      - Lega Tribe [Slide box 12] (Box 2)
      - Lengola People (Box 2)
      - Luba People (Box 2)
      - Mangbetu Tribe (Box 2)
      - Mayumbe Tribe (Box 2)
      - Mbola People (Box 2)
      - Mboma People (Box 2)
      - Ngbaka Tribe (Box 2)
      - Nkanu People (Box 2)
      - Pende People (Box 2)
      - Pere Tribe (Box 2)
      - Songye People (Box 2)
      - Suku Tribe (Box 2)
      - Teke People (Box 2)
      - Tshokwe (Box 2)
      - Tu-Chockwe [Slide boxes 12-13] (Box 2–3)
      - Yaka People [Slide box 13] (Box 3)
  - East Africa (Box 3)
    - Various (Box 3)
    - Makonde Tribe (Box 3)
  - North Africa (Box 3)
    - Various (Box 3)
  - South Africa (Box 3)
    - Various (Box 3)
- Architecture (Box 3)
  - General (Box 3)
    Xx for Maps see Maps Primitive Africa
    - Various (Box 3)
  - West Africa (Box 3)
    - General [Slide boxes 13-14] (Box 3)
      - Construction [Slide box 14] (Box 3)
      - Houses (Box 3)
      - Architecture by People (Box 3)
        - Various (Box 3)
        - Bamileke people (Box 3)
        - Conjagi people (Box 3)
        - Dogon people (Box 3)
        - Fuguli people (Box 3)
        - Kassena people [Slide boxes 14-15] (Box 3)
        - Ko people [Slide box 15] (Box 3)
        - Kusasi people (Box 3)
        - Lela people (Box 3)
        - Mousgoun people (Box 3)
        - Nankani people (Box 3)
        - Nuna people (Box 3)
        - Susu people (Box 3)
      - Architecture by site (Box 3)
        - Various (Box 3)
        - Cameroon (Box 3)
          - Various (Box 3)
          - Bametchuetcha (Box 3)
          - Bandjoun (Box 3)
        - Dahomey (Box 3)
          - Abomey (Box 3)
          - Bassila (Box 3)
          - Bohicon (Box 3)
          - Dassa Zoume (Box 3)
          - Ganvie (Box 3)
          - Ketu (Box 3)
          - Savalou (Box 3)
        - Ghana (Box 3)
          - Various (Box 3)
          - Akropong (Box 3)
          - Kusami (Box 3)
        - Guinea (Box 3)
          - Various (Box 3)
          - Bissau Island (Box 3)
          - Katako (Box 3)
        - Mali (Box 3)
          - Various (Box 3)
          - Diafarabe (Box 3)
          - Diohou (Box 3)
          - Djenne (Box 3)
          - Kateen [Slide box 16] (Box 3)
          - Kidal (Box 3)
          - Mopti (Box 3)
          - Timbuktu (Box 3)
        - Mauritania (Box 3)
          - Various (Box 3)
          - Koumbi Saleh (Box 3)
          - Oualata (Box 3)
          - Qasr El-Barka (Box 3)
        - Nigeria (Box 3)
          - Various (Box 3)
          - Kano (Box 3)
          - Owerri (Box 3)
          - Pobe (Box 3)
          - Zaria (Box 3)
        - Senegal (Box 3)
          - Various (Box 3)
          - Casamanca (Box 3)
          - Kamobeul (Box 3)
        - Upper Volta (Box 3)
          - Bobo-Dioulasso (Box 3)
          - Kampala (Box 3)
          - Kokosso [Slide box 17] (Box 3)
          - Koumi (Box 3)
          - Po (Box 3)
          - Sissili (Box 3)
          - Zecco (Box 3)
  - East Africa (Box 3)
    - Various (Box 3)
  - Central Africa (Box 3)
    - Various (Box 3)
  - North Africa (Box 3)
    - Various (Box 3)
  - South Africa (Box 3)
    - Zimbabwe (Box 3)
- African Modern (Box 3)
  - Various Artists (Box 3)
  - Anatsui, El, 1944- (Box 3)
  - Bouabre, Frederic Bruly, 1923- (Box 3)
  - Gutsa, Tapfuma (Box 3)
  - Kingelez, Bodys Isek, 1948- (Box 3)
  - Kossi, Agbagli, 1934- (Box 3)
  - Lakhdar, Boujemaa, 1945- (Box 3)
  - Munyaradzi, Henry, 1933- (Box 3)
  - Outtara, 1957- (Box 3)
- Afro (Box 3)
  [Slide box 18]
  - Various (Box 3)
  - Afro-Brazilian (Box 3)
    Xx Painting Brazil –Caribe, B., Leirner, N., Oliveira, R., Prazeres, H., Adelson
    Xx Sculpture Brazil –Santos, A., General, Louco and G.T.O.
    Xx Architecture 19th –20th c. Brazil
    - Various (Box 3)
  - Afro-Cuban (Box 3)
    - Various (Box 3)
    - Dance (Box 3)
    - Musical Instruments (Box 3)
    - Painting (Box 3)
  - Afro-Haitian (Box 3)
    Xx for other Haitian Painters see: Painting Caribbean Haiti
    - Various [Slide boxes 18-19] (Box 3–4)
  - Afro-Mexican [Slide box 19] (Box 4)
    - Various (Box 4)
  - Afro-Portuguese (Box 4)
    - Various (Box 4)
  - Afro-Surinam (Box 4)
    - Various (Box 4)
  - Afro-Trinidad (Box 4)
    - Various (Box 4)
  - Afro-Venezuela (Box 4)
    - Various (Box 4)
  - Afro-United States (Box 4)
    Xx for Furniture, see Furniture U.S
    Xx for Photography U.S., Miner, Leigh Richmond
    - Various [Slide boxes 19-20] (Box 4)
    - Architecture [Slide box 20] (Box 4)
      Xx Architecture U.S., South Carolina, Mulberry Castle Plantation.
    - Basketry (Box 4)
    - Ceramics (Box 4)
    - Costume (Box 4)
    - Music (Box 4)
    - Sculpture (Box 4)
    - Textiles [Slide boxes 20-21] (Box 4)
- Native American Modern (Box 4)
  [Slide box 21]
  - Various (Box 4)
    Xx Smith, Jaune Quick-to-See (Painting U.S.)
- North (Native) American Indian (Box 4)
  - Various (Box 4)
  - Early Depictions (Box 4)
    Xx for Painting of Two Indian chiefs on Wall of Warner House, Portsmouth, N.H., see Painting U.S. 18th c.
    Xx for Drawings, Painting U.S. John White, Prints Flanders de Bry
  - Alaskan Arctic: Eskimo, Alaska (Box 4)
  - Alaskan Arctic: Inupiaq, North Alaska (Box 4)
  - West Subarctic: Athabaskan (Box 4)
  - West Subarctic: Ingalik (Box 4)
  - Californian (Box 4)
  - Northwest Coast (Box 4)
    - Various (Box 4)
    - Peoples (Box 4)
      - Bella Coola (Box 4)
      - Haida [Slide box 22] (Box 4)
      - Kwakiutl (Box 4)
      - Nootka-Makah (Box 4)
      - Salish (Box 4)
      - Tlingit (Box 4)
      - Tsimshia (Box 4)
  - Plains (Box 4)
    - General (Box 4)
    - Sites (Box 4)
      - Cuttle Lake, Ontario (Box 4)
      - Eagle Cave, Texas [Slide box 23] (Box 4)
      - Fate Bell Shelter, Texas (Box 4)
      - Hueco Tanks, Texas (Box 4)
      - Meyers Springs, Texas (Box 4)
      - Panther Cave, Texas (Box 4)
      - Pecos River, Texas (Box 4)
      - Rattlesnake Canyon, Texas (Box 4)
    - Peoples (Box 4)
      - Apache (Box 4)
      - Arapaho (Box 4)
      - Blackfoot (Box 4)
      - Cheyenne (Box 4)
      - Cree (Box 4)
      - Crow (Box 4)
      - Kiowa (Box 4)
      - Mandan (Box 4)
      - Pawnee (Box 4)
      - Sioux (Box 4)
        - Sioux, Dakota (Box 4)
        - Sioux, Oglala (Box 4)
  - Mississippi Valley (Box 4)
  - Mississippi Valley Cahokia (Box 4)
  - C. Woodland (Box 4)
  - E. Woodland (Box 4)
    - Various (Box 4)
    - Sites (Box 4)
      - Various (Box 4)
      - Adena Mound, Ross County, OH (Box 4)
      - Baum Works, OH (Box 4)
      - Big Toco Mound, TN (Box 4)
      - Coffee County, TN (Box 4)
      - Etowah Mound, GA [Slide box 24] (Box 4)
      - Fort Ancient, OH (Box 4)
      - Gadsden County, FL (Box 4)
      - Grave Creek Mound, OH (Box 4)
      - Great Serpent Mound, OH (Box 4)
      - High Bank, OH (Box 4)
      - Hopetown Works, OH (Box 4)
      - Hopewell Mound, OH (Box 4)
      - Key Marco, FL. (Box 4)
      - Liberty Township Works, OH (Box 4)
      - Malden, Dunklin Co., MO (Box 4)
      - Marietta Works, OH (Box 4)
      - Megis County, OH (Box 4)
      - Mound City, OH (Box 4)
      - Moundville, AL (Box 4)
      - Murfreesboro, TN (Box 4)
      - Newark Works, OH (Box 4)
      - Ross County, OH (Box 4)
      - Spiro Mound, OK (Box 4)
      - Sumner County, TN (Box 4)
      - Tremper Mound, OH (Box 4)
      - Turner Mounds (Box 4)
      - White River, Ark (Box 4)
      - Wilson County, TN (Box 4)
    - Peoples (Box 4)
      - Various (Box 4)
      - Hopewell culture (Box 4)
      - Iroquois [Slide box 25] (Box 5)
      - Massachusetts (Box 5)
      - Micmac (Box 5)
  - Southwest (Box 5)
    - General (Box 5)
    - Sites (Box 5)
      - Various (Box 5)
      - Acoma (Box 5)
      - Awatori Pueblo (Box 5)
      - Aztec Ruins, NM (Box 5)
      - Betatakin Pueblo (Box 5)
      - Casa Rinconada (Box 5)
      - Chaco Canyon (Box 5)
      - Chetro Ketl (Box 5)
      - Cochiti (Box 5)
      - Kawaika-A (Box 5)
      - Kiet Siel Pueblo (Box 5)
      - Mesa Verde [Slide boxes 25-26] (Box 5)
      - Pueblo Bonito [Slide box 26] (Box 5)
      - San Ildefonso Pueblo (Box 5)
      - San Juan Pueblo (Box 5)
      - Taos (Box 5)
      - Tesuque Pueblo (Box 5)
      - Red Paint Pueblo (Box 5)
    - Peoples (Box 5)
      - Various (Box 5)
      - Anasazi [Slide boxes 26-27] (Box 5)
      - Hohokam [Slide box 27] (Box 5)
      - Hopi (Box 5)
      - Mimbres (Box 5)
      - Mogollon [Slide box 28] (Box 5)
    - Navajo (Box 5)
      - Various (Box 5)
      - Blankets (Box 5)
    - Tewa (Box 5)
    - Zuni (Box 5)
- Pacific [Islands] (Box 5)
  - Various locations (Box 5)